micropoll.com 2016-12-09

# MicroPoll Privacy Policy QuestionPro Online Survey Software

## QuestionPro Privacy Policy  
Effective Date: July 21, 2016 

This Privacy Policy applies to [http://www.micropoll.com](http://www.micropoll.com/) (“MicroPoll”) owned and operated by QuestionPro. This Privacy Statement describes how [http://www.micropoll.com](http://www.micropoll.com/) collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. 

QuestionPro has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Website: [www.micropoll.com](http://www.micropoll.com/) and does not cover our mobile application or information collected by our customers using our service. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

## General Information

This privacy policy applies to MicroPoll products, services, research panels, sub-research panels and any other research panels created, maintained, and/or operated by MicroPoll and/or its affiliates, subsidiaries and/or divisions. MicroPoll strives to conform its privacy practices, policies and/or procedures with any and all applicable international, country specific, US federal, state and/or local laws, codes, regulations, and requirements and the industry codes, standards and regulations of various market and opinion research professional associations and/ or organizations, including without limitation the ICC/ESOMAR International Code on Market and Social Research and the Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO). MicroPoll is committed to protecting the security and integrity of all personal information collected by or disclosed to MicroPoll. MicroPoll will not use any personal information for direct marketing or advertising purposes and membership as a research panel member and/or participation in any surveys are completely voluntary. This privacy policy identifies the personal information that MicroPoll collects; how such personal information will be used and protected; and your rights. 

## INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

## Registration

In order to use this Web site, you must first complete the registration form and create a username and password. During registration you are required to give your name and contact information (including email address). We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest. After registering with the site, we use your email address to provide you with a series of 'Ongoing Communications and Product Updates' (see 'Communication from the Site'). These communications are used to give you a better understanding of the site, what it offers, and how it is best utilized. As always, you have the option not to receive these types of communications (see 'Choice and Opt-out' in ‘Information Sharing and Disclosure’). 

## Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. We will also use this information to send you 'Service-related Communications' (see 'Communication from the Site'). These include email confirmations of billing transactions, account upgrades, and account cancellations. Please see the 'Contact Us' below. 

## Profile

We store information that we collect through user input, cookies, log files, and user surveys to create a 'profile' of preferences. This profile information includes each of the following categories: 

Registration Information: username, password, first name, last name, email address, phone 

Order Information: credit card number, credit card, expiration, billing address 

Preferences: profile information that categorizes how the software is utilized 

Details of the user profile are used to contact the user (see 'Communication from the Site') and provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the site. 

Profile information may be updated at any time by clicking on the 'My Account' link while the user is logged into their administrative account. 

## SURVEYS OR CONTESTS

If you are a member of a MicroPoll research panel, we may from time- to-time provide you with the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and/or username), and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information gain knowledge about our users and their experience using the site. 

## FORWARD TO FRIEND/ADD A USER

A respondent may share a survey with other users by providing email addresses after completing the survey. MicroPoll will automatically send a survey link to those addresses and a one-time email that introduces and invites the addressee to the MicroPoll site. We will not share these email addresses with customers or survey administrators and will not send future mailings unless the addressee requests further communication. Any addressee who has been referred to our site or surveys may contact [support-team@surveyanalytics.com](mailto:support-team@surveyanalytics.com) (or use the “Contact Us” link on our homepage) and request to be removed from the database. When you add a new user to your account, such as the “Add User” function on your MicroPoll account, we collect that user’s name, email address and other contact information. MicroPoll stores this information for the sole purpose of providing this service to you as our MicroPoll customer. You or the added user may request to delete this submitted information by contacting us at [support-team@surveyanalytics.com](mailto:support-team@surveyanalytics.com). 

## USES OF INFORMATION

Any information shared with MicroPoll during the creation of a survey is owned solely by the administrator of that survey. By the nature of how our service works, surveys need to be shared via a URL on the Internet. We provide the option to password-protect your surveys if they contain sensitive content. Email addresses uploaded to the system for the purpose of sending survey invitations and email communication are owned solely by the survey administrator. We will never share any information uploaded to the system with any 3rd parties. Data collected through surveys is owned solely by the survey administrator. By default, the data is only accessible by providing a username and password and logging into the site. There is the option to share online reports via a URL from the administrative account. The survey administrator controls this option. We will never use any of the data collected. MicroPoll may collect the Internet protocol address (the IP address) that is publicly available on your computer. The IP address is not collected for the purpose of tracking or monitoring your activity on the Internet. In non-United States jurisdictions, an IP address may be classified as personal information or personal data under applicable laws; therefore, to the extent that MicroPoll collects IP addresses, MicroPoll will collect, use, maintain, secure and/or disclose IP addresses in accordance with applicable Laws. 

## COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE

## Ongoing Communication and Product Updates

We will occasionally send you information on product enhancements, new services, and additional instruction on utilizing our services. These communications are designed to educate our users on the services offered. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see “Choice and Opt-out” in “Information Sharing and Disclosure.” **Service-related Announcements** We will send you strictly service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Service-related emails are also sent confirming billing transactions, account upgrades, and account cancellations. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to cancel your account. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to cancel your account. 

## Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password as well an account manager contact information. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. 

## Survey Invitations

If you are a member of a MicroPoll research panel, we may, from time-to-time, send you email invitations to surveys. We may also periodically send you emails regarding research panel information and communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide information you request. 

## INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

## Personally Identifiable Information Sharing with Partners

We do not share any personally identifiable information with any third parties except as indicated below. If a user specifically requests a service from one of our partnering companies, their personally identifying information will be shared. The partnering company may contact them directly regarding their inquiry. Any requests of partnering companies are initiated solely by the user, and it will be clearly indicated that a partnering company offers the requested service. We may use the third-party research panel providers to provide survey respondents for clients who request online survey panels. When you request access to such an online survey panel, your contact information will be shared with third-party research panel providers as necessary for them to provide that service. Third-party research panel providers are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We use a third-party service provider to host chat support on our site. When you request live chat support, your contact information will be stored by the service provider as necessary for it to provide its service. The service provider is prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We use outside credit card processing companies to bill you for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or similar legal process. If MicroPoll is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding personally identifiable information. 

## CHOICE/OPT-OUT

If you no longer wish to receive our product updates, you may opt out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each product update email. If you are a member of a MicroPoll research panel, you may opt out of membership in our research panels by following instructions included in each survey invitation. 

## TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by MicroPoll and MicroPoll affiliates, marketing partners, analytics providers and online customer support providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We use cookies for user authentication purposes. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

## BULLETIN BOARDS/CHAT ROOMS/ FORUM

If you use a bulletin board or chat room or public forum on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit it here can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or public forum, contact us at [privacy@questionpro.com](mailto:privacy@questionpro.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

## TESTIMONIALS

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@questionpro.com](mailto:privacy@questionpro.com). 

## IMPORT CONTACTS

You can import contacts from your email account address book to invite them to take part in surveys. We collect the username and password for the email account you provide and will only use such information for the purpose of inviting contacts to take part in surveys. 

## ACCESS TO PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update, delete or cancel your account at any time by logging into the system and clicking on the “My Account” link. Options for updating your profile and account cancellations are available. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. 

## DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## SECURITY

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as credit card number on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

## LINKS TO 3RD PARTY SITES

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of MicroPoll. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit. 

## SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## SINGLE SIGN-ON

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

## CHANGES IN THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective. 

## CONTACT US

MicroPoll is committed to working with individuals to obtain a fair resolution to any complaints or disputes about privacy and personal information. MicroPoll commitment to privacy is demonstrated and documented by our internal Privacy Compliance Officer, by our adherence to the applicable laws and codes. If you have any complaints or concerns about this privacy policy you can contact: 

    Anup Surendran
    Privacy Compliance Officer
    MicroPoll
    548 Market St #62790
    San Francisco, CA 94104-5401
    Email: [ privacy@questionpro.com](mailto:privacy@questionpro.com)

    United States of America: +1 (800) 531-0228
    United Kingdom: +44 20 7558 8080
    Australia: +61 2 8005 0459
    Fax: +1 (206) 260-3243
